ANDREW TERRELL

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

International business, communications, economics, and political professional with over 10 years of experience in public affairs serving over 140 organizations globally. Proven success in leadership, government affairs, operations, project management, and research. Keen eye for mitigating risk and relationship building. Adaptable, mission-oriented, focused on delivering value, and a reliable anchor for any team. Values interdisciplinary and multicultural perspectives. --US Citizen--

RECENT EXPERIENCE

British Consul of Business & Government Affairs 2016 – 2020 British Embassy (HMG-FCO) - DC, GA, NC, SC, VA, UK

- Public-facing diplomatic representative.
- Account managed critical relationships with over 250 business leaders and political stakeholders, supervising over 300K points of contact.
- Provided counsel to HM Ambassador, cabinet officials, policy leads, and embassy team on a wide array of federal and state affairs.
- Built and managed a new diplomatic affairs office focused on statelevel business and government relations. Led economic and political reporting, ministerial and VIP visits, crisis response activities.
- Assisted in managing a \$1.7M project budget, \$200B in trade, and \$1T in FDI across diverse sectors (heavily AEM, life science, and tech).
- Managed intergovernmental teams on delivery of senior level public policy projects (e.g. defense, diversity, energy, environment, trade)

Lead Intelligence Analyst (OSINT), Strategy & Product Dev 2014 – 2016 Cision, Bulletin Intelligence – DC, VA, EU, UK

- Produced customized intelligence reports to C-suite executives and government agencies around the world, including the Federal Drug Administration, Treasury Department, and White House.
- Managed collaboration between global teams to develop new data products for improved risk management and decision-making.
- Provided consistent high-quality strategic media, political, and policy analyses to high-profile clients within tight deadlines.
- Directed implementation of new business intelligence tools, selecting appropriate solutions and aiding in corresponding processes.
- Evaluated consistency and importance of different business intelligence data to determine optimal delivery strategy.
- Mapped process activities to identify shortfalls and propose options to rectify operational inefficiencies.

CONTACT

Phone: +1.828.238.7406

Email: andrew.terrell@me.com

EDUCATION

Master's, International Political
Economy & Law, 2013
Warwick University — Coventry, UK
UK Russell Group Research Institution
Research Assistant, Econ Dept;
Published in the Roo Institute's 10
Ideas in Econ Development Journal;
Departmental Distinction Award.

Bachelor's — International Relations, Political Science, and Economics, 2010 Richmond American International University (LSE Joint) - London, UK Sr. Thesis Award; Student of the Year; U.S.-Japan Diplomatic Fellowship.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Served on the White House's National Economic Council, National Security Staff, and OSTP.
- Appointed to Her Majesty's Diplomatic Service.
- Consulted for OSD and members of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
- Supervised over \$400M in business development and trade accounts.
- Fellow, Securing America's Energy
 Future
- Organized, hosted PM Cameron visit and various cabinet Ministers.
- Co-Founded two companies.
- Raised over \$25,000 for charities.
- Led UK D&I efforts.

Defense & Legislative Policy Analyst 2013 – 2014 McAleese & Associates – DC, VA

- Advised aerospace companies, financial firms, and the Secretary of Defense (OSD) on budgetary, legal, policy, and technical matters.
- Provided economic and technical analysis of the impact on the defense industry base of DoD procurement decisions.
- Managed analysis of Congressional and agency budgets to model impact on acquisition, logistics, and technology capabilities.
- Produced daily deliverables, including real-time analysis on defense programs, contractor operations, mergers, and CIFIUS reviews.
- Generated reports of findings to help management with making key decisions. Senior Editor for all RFP responses.
- Used Excel to model data and forecast trends that consistently attracted new business.

National Economic Council Fellow 2012 - 2013 The White House - DC

- Analyzed qualitative and quantitative research to deliver economic policy analysis to the NEC and President of the United States.
- Provided analysis and research to the finance, housing, national security, and technology policy teams (NSS and OSTP).
- Managed large sets of domestic and international macroeconomic data for the White House and several agencies.
- Produced daily briefings on crisis issues, including the Eurocrisis, housing market, and at-risk international financial markets.
- Prepared policy briefing materials for major international summits, including Jackson Hole.

Sr Policy Consultant and Project Manager 2010 – 2020 TG Consulting – CA, DC, GA, MD, NC, NY, VA, EU, JP, UK

- Managed a specialized consultancy team focused on multidisciplinary international business, economics, intelligence, and data projects.
- Produced detailed strategic reporting deliverables for decision makers. These included market intelligence, public policy analyses, and specialized macroeconomic research. Ghost wrote op-eds and contributed to RFP responses.
- Offered strategic recommendations for research methodologies and policies to mitigate perceived bias based on current political trends.
- End users included Fortune 500 companies, governments, media, nonprofits, and advising political principals.

SKILLS

- · Business administration
- Business analysis
- Business development
- Cultural adaptability
- · Cross-functional communication
- Data collection and analysis
- Economic analysis
- Multidisciplinary research
- · Multi-purpose writing and editing
- Political analysis
- Project management
- Public policy development, research
- Public speaking
- · Strategic planning
- Teaching and curricula development
- Operational management
- Relationship management
- · Research management
- Risk analysis
- Languages: English, native;
 Japanese, working proficiency (N3);
 Spanish, working proficiency.
- Technical skills: Bloomberg, Haver, HTML, LexisNexis, MS Office (inc. Excel), Python, R/RStudio, SQL.

AFFLIATIONS

- American Economic Association
- British-American Business Council
- Kiwanis International
- National Economists Club
- Securing America's Energy Future
- Royal Society for the Arts,
 Commerce, and Manufacturing
- U.S. Air Force Association
- White House Alumni Association
- Warwick Alumni Association
- Young Professionals in Foreign Policy